MANISH SINGH

771/83, Near Chanakya Classes, Gokhalenagar, Pune - 411016 +91-9975610409

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer w/1.5 years of experience worked in product/web development.

Recently, worked on improving products and services for clients enhancing and maintaining multiple modules of several

Excellent in debugging, code-fix and enhancement of product.

EXPERIENCE

Yardi Software India Private Limited

July 2016 - May 2017

Software Engineer Trainee

Role: Programming, Analytics/SSRS reports Enhancement of product through:

- ✓ Worked on real estate management products using C#, VB.NET, web-services, WCF, SQL Server 2012,2014, MVC4, Entity-Framework, LINQ and TFS 2012,2013, 2015 and robust technology of Visual Studio Premium 2012, 2013, 2015
- ✓ Query optimization using T-SQL, Stored Procedures, Triggers, and Function.
- ✓ Check-in the files through VS TFS and delivered before release dates with accuracy by performing unit testing for all the deliverables of plugins of multiple modules.
- ✓ Worked closely with QA to resolve the plugins
- ✓ Prepared analytics and SSRS reports
- ✓ Framework and database schema along with different products set-up
- ✓ working and setup knowledge of IIS.

Yardi Software India Private Limited

January 2016 - July 2016

Intern

Application Name: CPR Repository & CSD Toolbox Language: VB.NET, C#

An application which is precisely a search-based windows application where text files serve a greater importance.

EDUCATION

Fergusson College, Savitribai Phule Pune University

2016

Master of Technology (Industrial Mathematics with Computer Applications) with 64.41

D. G. Ruparel College, University of Mumbai

2013

Bachelor of Science(Mathematics) with 56.61

2010

H. S. C. with 63.83

P. S. D. E. M. S. S. S. C. with 74

2008

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Operating System: Windows (Windows 10, Windows7), UNIX (Linux, Macintosh, Ubuntu)

Object oriented: C++, C#, VB.NET, Java
Web Technologies: ASP.NET, ADO.NET, Entity- Framework, MVC4, WCF, Web Services

Scripting Languages: JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, AngularJS

IDE: Visual Studio Premium 2012, 2013, 2015 Database: SQL server 2012,2014, SSRS

Tools: TFS 2012, 2013, 2015

Area of Interest: Object-oriented design, Java, Android. Unix/Linux OS, Mac OS X.

Mobile Operating System: Blackberry OS, Android OS, iOS

PROJECT

Kernel Module

Kernel modules are pieces of code that can be loaded and unloaded into kernel upon demand. Simple hello world the kernel module is written. Extend the functionality of kernel without a need to reboot the system.

Language: C Platform: Linux

Tool Chain Explorer

This is the implementation of converting C source file into machine dependent language using Linux commands. Language: C Platform: Linux

ACHIEVEMENTS

"Student Placement Coordinator" at Fergusson College, 2015 - 2016

& AWARDS

"Superintendent" of the Fergusson Boy's Hostel for the year 2014 - 2015.

PERSONAL PROFILE

Date of Birth : 04/09/1991

Marital Status : Single Nationality : Indian

Languages Known : English, Hindi, Marathi